<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Takahashi Group</title>
    <link>http://takahashigroup.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://takahashigroup.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Takahashi Group</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://takahashigroup.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Takahashi Group</title>
      <link>http://takahashigroup.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Group Principles</title>
      <link>http://takahashigroup.github.io/principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://takahashigroup.github.io/principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Takahashi Group conducts research while adhering to these principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shared value with the community&lt;/h3&gt;
We believe that the information and knowledge we come across should also be shared with others and the community at large.
&lt;h3&gt;Open Source&lt;/h3&gt;
We believe in open source code for transparency of our work. 
We hope people learn from codes and share the knowledge and skills with others.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Takahashi Group primarily develops code that fall under GPL or MIT licenses. You can read more about these licences &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/licenses.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The official operating system used within Takahashi Group is Linux Mint.
&lt;h3&gt;Open Data&lt;/h3&gt;
Anyone should be able to access scientific data.
&lt;h3&gt;DIY &amp; Building from Scratch&lt;/h3&gt;
We at Takahashi Group build our servers and experimental equipment from scratch. 
In doing so, it is possible to understand the physical aspects that affect our research, allowing us to maximize the power that such machines are able to offer.
&lt;h3&gt;Learning from Failure&lt;/h3&gt;
Science is all about failure. We report failures and all results honestly. Failed results are key towards success in science.
&lt;h3&gt;Open for Collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;
We welcome collaborations with others. Please contact me &lt;b&gt;(keisuke.takahashi[at]sci.hokudai.ac.jp)&lt;/b&gt; if you are interested collaborating with us.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Research</title>
      <link>http://takahashigroup.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://takahashigroup.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Takahashi Group focuses on the design of materials, catalysts, and chemical reactions in a combination of experiments, theory, computations, and data science.
To do this, we focus on research in four different areas: &lt;b&gt;Database Construction&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Experiment &amp;amp; Calculation&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Data Science&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;Software Development&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;4informatics.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Database construction&lt;/u&gt; is carried out using data collected from high-throughput experiments and calculations as well as literature data.
&lt;u&gt;Data science&lt;/u&gt; endeavors involve artificial intelligence, machine learning, visualization, or some combination of the aforementioned techniques.
&lt;u&gt;Experiments and calculations&lt;/u&gt; are used to design and test various catalysts and reactions.
&lt;u&gt;Software development&lt;/u&gt; includes developing the CADS platform, which is a materials informatics platform designed for sharing material data and providing on-site informatics tools that are accessible for experts and non-experts alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;By addressing these four areas, we are able to cover aspects of four types of informatics: Materials Informatics・Catalyst Informatics・ Measurement Informatics・Process Informatics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Current Areas of Research&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current research topics fall within the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Materials Informatics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Catalysts Informatics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measurement Informatics &amp;amp; Signal Processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atomic Clusters &amp;amp; Cluster Assembled Materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heterogeneous Catalysts &amp;amp; Energy Materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials Informatics&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
Materials informatics is the field where data science and materials science are integrated. We implement various data science techniques including machine learning, multi-dimensional visualization, and statistics towards designing materials.
&lt;img src=&#34;1.PNG&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Catalysts Informatics&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
Materials informatics is applied in catalysis where data science is implemented for seeking catalysts as well as optimizing the experimental process conditions during the reactions. For further details concerning this work, please visit the Catalysts Informatics project page. http://catalystinfo.eng.hokudai.ac.jp/index-e.html
&lt;img src=&#34;2.PNG&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Measurement Informatics &amp; Signal Processing&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
Materials Informatics is also applied in the field of measurements. In particular, spectra gained from XAFS, Raman, and EELS are intensively analyzed using data science where algorithms for decomposing such complex peaks are also investigated.
&lt;img src=&#34;3.PNG&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Atomic Clusters &amp; Cluster-Assembled Materials&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
Atomic clusters consist of few to hundreds of atoms. Because of the high surface to volume ratio, properties of clusters are different from their bulk and nanoparticle counterparts. We treat those small clusters as building blocks for designing further complex and unique crystals.
&lt;img src=&#34;4.PNG&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Heterogeneous Catalysts &amp; Energy Materials&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
By combining experiment, theory, computation, and data science, we are designing unique and novel Heterogeneous Catalysts and Energy Materials. We design two dimensional materials; zeolites; oxide surfaces for COx and NOx; and CH4 activation. For energy materials, we are designing high performence two dimensional materials and perovskite materials for gas storage as well as photovoltaic cell applications.
&lt;img src=&#34;5.PNG&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Interested in joining?&lt;/h1&gt;
Please contact me &lt;b&gt;(keisuke.takahashi[at]sci.hokudai.ac.jp)&lt;/b&gt; if you are interested in working on the above research.
I have several suggestions for Masters, PhD, and Post-Doc.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Takahashi Group Homepage</title>
      <link>http://takahashigroup.github.io/post/22-11-17-lab-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://takahashigroup.github.io/post/22-11-17-lab-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Takahashi Group homepage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Takahashi Group (情報化学研究室)!
We are a research group based out of the Department of Chemistry at Hokkaido University.
Takahashi Group focuses on the design of materials, catalysts, and chemical reactions in a combination of experiments, theory, computations, and data science.
We focus on research in four different areas: &lt;b&gt;Database Construction&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Experiment &amp;amp; Calculation&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Data Science&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;Software Development&lt;/b&gt;.
In doing so, our research helps develop aspects of four types of informatics: &lt;b&gt;Materials Informatics&lt;/b&gt;・&lt;b&gt;Catalyst Informatics&lt;/b&gt;・ &lt;b&gt;Measurement Informatics&lt;/b&gt;・&lt;b&gt;Process Informatics&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find us here:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
〒060-0810&lt;br&gt;
札幌市北区北１０条西８丁目&lt;br&gt;
北海道大学大学院 理学研究院化学部門 理学部7号館510号室&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Hokkaido University, Faculty of Science,  Department of Chemistry,&lt;br&gt;
7th building, Room 7-510, Kita 10, Nishi 8, Kita-ku,&lt;br&gt;
Sapporo, 060-0810, Japan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://takahashigroup.github.io/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://takahashigroup.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://takahashigroup.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://takahashigroup.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://takahashigroup.github.io/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://takahashigroup.github.io/people/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
